( water laps / seagulls cry )
( sniffs )
You were just having a bad dream , that 's all , baby .
That 's all it was .
Bad dreams make you think you 've seen things that you haven 't .
You know what I do when I have a bad dream ?
I close my eyes and I think of something nice .
Like being here with you .
( children chatter )
Hurry up , sweetheart . I can 't be late .
( seagulls cry )
( doorbell )
( sighs ) Shit !
( lawnmower whirs )
- Jack ? - ( mower stops )
- Did you see someone ring my bell ? - No .
OK , thanks .
I cleaned everything away , sweetheart !
Everything 's exactly how it was before .
- No ! No ! - The floors are clean and shiny .
- Look . You see ? - ( wails )
OK , alright , just close your eyes .
( seagull cries )
- ( man ) Well , hello , sailor ! - ( woman ) Hi !
Permission to come aboard ?
Honey , hold this .
Sorry we couldnt make it yesterday . Somebody was working late again !
How you doing , Sal ?
- I 'm good . How are you ? - I 'm alright .
Look at you .
- You like it ? - You look great .
Really ? It 's nothing . I just threw it on .
Bullshit . She 's had outfits laid out for a week .
You 're such a liar ! Ignore my husband , please .
I don 't listen to a word he says .
I brought really good friend , Heather .
Promise me you 'll be attentive .
- How you doing , man ? - I asked you not to bring anyone .
You don 't like her ? Believe me , she 's the best-looking of Sally 's friends .
Which , granted , isn 't saying much .
I asked you not to .
( sighs ) You live on a boat with an 18-year-old boy
and you ask me not to bring girls ?
Greg , this is Heather .
She 's a very good friend of mine and , er , I thought you guys should meet .
- Hi . - Hi .
Can you just excuse me for a moment ?
- Jess . Are you OK ? - I don 't think so .
Hey . What happened ?
Hey ! What 's the matter ?
- I 'm sorry . - You got nothing to apologise for .
What is it ? Are you OK ?
I 'm just tired .
We don 't have to go today if you don 't want to .
No , I do . | - I wanna go .
Are you sure ?
Yeah . Yeah .
Yeah ? OK , come on , come meet the gang .
- Sally , and her husband , Downey . - Hi .
This is Heather . You remember Victor .
So let 's go sailing !
( Victor ) OK !
( seagull cries )
( Heather ) Hey .
You OK ?
( sighs ) Is Greg OK ?
He 's fine . He 's upstairs . You 've been asleep for a couple of hours .
I had this terrible dream .
- What about ? - I don 't remember .
I wouldn 't worry .
Apparently , bad dreams cure you of real-life stress .
As indeed does champagne ! You want some ?
Yeah .
Downey , wanna give me a hand , please ?
Actually , Victor , I 'm a guest of the captains ,
but , yes , I will help you .
Victor , what was that back there at the harbour ?
What ?
I asked Jess if she was alright , and you said no .
You told me she was bringing a little boy along .
When I was walking with her , I asked her where he was and ...
Well , she couldn 't remember .
She stared into space for 20 seconds , and then she said he 's at school .
So ?
Well , it 's Saturday . There ain 't no school today .
Her son goes to a special needs school and it 's open every day .
Be nice to her .
- Alright . - Alright .
So , do you boys sunbathe together ?
Sometimes .
The champagne 's not great , but it is cold .
- Want some ? - No , thanks .
OK , more for me .
Hey . How you feeling ?
Sorry . I didn 't realise how tired I was .
You apologise one more time and I 'm gonna throw you overboard .
Here .
- You alright ? - Yeah .
( wind gusts )
( seagull cries )
It thinks we 're a fishing boat . He 's gonna go hungry .
- You wanna steer ? - No .
- Go on . - Oh ...
Oop !
Which way do I aim ?
You wanna aim that way .
It 's easy , right ?
( Heather ) She 's a waitress at some diner .
He eats there , they talked , they became friends .
Oh , and she has an autistic son .
- So , they 're just friends ? - Sally !
Do you want me to say I 'm sorry she has a retarded son ?
- Yeah ! - Well , I 'm sorry .
But you know , that 's not Greg 's problem , that 's hers .
- What is it ? Is it the shorts ? - No !
Heather , Greg 's been my friend for a really long time .
I can 't sit back and watch him get shaken down .
She isn 't doing that .
Well , I hope not , because Greg is far too trusting .
I 'm kinda liking the boy !
No , you 're not . Can you please go up there and talk to Greg ?
I really think the two of you would be perfect for each other .
And I really don 't like seeing him with her .
Jess , you ready ?
Yeah , let her go !
( Greg ) Yeah ! Whoo !
( Jess ) How do you know everyone ?
( Greg ) Victor 's staying with me for a bit .
He got into some trouble at home .
I found him sleeping behind the store at the harbour . We got talking ...
- And now he lives here . - Just like that ?
- You let him move in ? - I got three rooms .
I can 't sleep in them all .
And Downey , I 've known him since I was a kid .
And Sally , his wife , I know her from high school .
I dated her for four days in the eighth grade ,
so , technically , she 's my ex .
- They seem really nice . - Yeah .
Except for the fact that every year ,
they feel obliged to bring me an eligible girl .
Maybe they think you 're lonely .
- Do I give off lonely to you ? - Sometimes .
When I come in to see you at the diner , I 'm not lonely , I 'm hungry .
Obviously yesterday was different .
- What happened yesterday ? - Well , yesterday , I was not hungry .
I came in with the sole purpose of inviting you sailing .
You did ?
I did .
Hey , turn her portside . We 're losing wind .
Here , let me take it for just a sec .
So , are things OK with Tommy ?
The same . Every day 's the same .
Tommy likes things to be a certain way .
If I do one thing differently , I lose him .
What 's the matter ? I 've never seen you like this before .
I don 't know . I just , er , feel guilty when I 'm not with Tommy .
That 's because you 're a good mother .
But you can 't be everywhere all of the time . It 's ...
( Heather ) Hey , guys . Oh ! ( laughs )
- How 's it going ? - We 're good .
I was just wondering if I could steal Jess away from you .
Sally 's dying to talk to her .
We 're kind of in the middle of something .
No , no , no . It 's OK . I should circulate .
Hey , just for the record ...
I 'm not interested .
Yo , what the fuck ... ?
Wind 's dropped out on us .
It 's not dropped . It 's gone .
( Victor ) This is crazy .
You ever seen this before ?
Yeah . Yeah , just not quite so sudden .
Are we OK to get home if there 's no wind ?
Yeah , yeah . We got an engine . It 's not a problem .
It 's just , it 's weird .
Greg ?
Is that normal ?
( thunder )
( Downey ) OK , I 'm fucking freaked now . What the fuck ?
- ( radio static ) - Triangle to coastguard . Over .
( static )
- Triangle to coastguard . Over . - ( static )
( man ) Coastguard . Go ahead . Over .
We 've just gone from seven knots to absolute zero .
You got anything unusual ? Over .
Nothing showing up . Over .
It 's darkening pretty quick . Looks like an electrical storm . Over .
- ( static ) - ( woman ) Help me .
Please , can you hear me ? ( gasps )
Help me ! Please , help me !
Killing everyone ! They 're dead ! They 're all dead !
We hear you . What 's your position ? Over .
Hurry ! Hurry !
Distress caller , we hear you . What are your coordinates ? Over .
( static )
Coastguard , did you hear a distress call ? Over .
Distress caller , make another transmission . What is your position ?
( Sally ) Greg !
Get below deck now ! Get the life jackets !
Cut it ! Cut the sail !
Vic ! Get the mainsail down ! Get it down !
- ( Sally whimpers ) - ( Greg ) Heather !
Vic !
- Get back ! - ( Jess ) Greg !
Jess , take my hand !
Grab on !
Heather !
Vic !
( gasps )
- Jess ! - ( gasps )
Jess , are you OK ?
Are you alright ?
( Downey coughs )
Downey ?
( gasps )
- You guys OK ? - Have you seen Heather ?
- She got washed out the window . - ( Greg ) No . Come on ! Come on !
- ( Downey ) Sally ! - Heather !
( Downey ) Climb on board . Do what Greg says .
Heather ? ( sobs )
( Sally ) Greg , help me ! Help me ! Can you see her ?
- ( Greg ) Just give me your hand . - ( Sally ) Heather !
- Are you guys OK ? - Yeah .
Are you alright ?
Tommy 's at school , yeah ?
He 'll be looked after until we get back . He 'll be alright .
( seagulls cry )
( distant rumbling )
( Victor ) Thank God ! Yo ! Help us !
( Sally ) Help us ! Please !
- ( Downey ) Over here ! - ( Sally ) Help us ! Please !
Oh ! Oh , God !
- Hey ! - Here !
- ( Sally ) Please ! - ( Greg ) Hey , come on ! Over here !
Hey , there , over there , I can see someone .
( Victor ) Yo ! We need some help down here !
- ( Downey ) Hey ! - ( Sally ) Help us , please !
Hello ! We need some help down here .
- ( Greg ) Yeah , he 's seen us . - ( Sally ) Help !
( Greg ) Oh , thank God .
Jump , jump , jump .
OK . Jess , come on , come on .
Jess , come on .
Come on . Take my hand . OK , good .
OK ? You made it .
- You OK ? - ( breathes heavily )
( engine roars )
( Downey pants )
- ( laughs ) You OK ? - ( sobs )
- We 're OK . - I know .
Hey !
( Greg ) See ? I told you . OK ?
Hello ?
Hello ? ( echoes )
Do we wait ?
Let 's go to the bridge . We 'll get the captain to call the coastguard .
- We 'll get a search on for Heather . - Yeah , OK .
Come on .
Do you think Heather made it on board ?
- Honey ... - There 's a chance .
( Downey ) Yeah . Yeah , there 's a chance .
( engine roars )
Hello ? ( echoes )
( tapping )
Hello ?
( Victor ) Hello ?
( Sally ) Can somebody please help us ?
Hello ?
( tapping )
( Victor ) Where the fuck is everybody ?
( Downey ) Do you know where we 're going ?
( Victor ) Uh-huh .
( Downey ) Or are we just ... just walking for the sake of it ?
Are you alright ?
I feel like I know this place .
I recognise this corridor .
Liners , they look ... pretty similar .
No , that 's not it .
( Victor ) Come check this out .
If this is the same ship , then this thing 's old .
Jess . Come on .
- ( Downey ) Yeah . - Come on .
( Downey ) 1932 . It is the same , see ?
- Here 's where we boarded . - ( Victor ) Oh , yeah .
- The Ay-oh-lus . - Aeolus .
" Aeolus was the Greek God of the winds and the father of Sisyphus ,
a man condemned by the gods to the task of pushing a rock up a mountain
only to see it roll down again . "
- Shitty punishment . What 'd he do ? - He cheated death .
No , he made a promise to death that he didn 't keep .
I 've studied it but I can 't remember . Can we just keep on moving , please ?
( metal clinks )
( distant footsteps )
( Greg ) Hello ?
( keys rattle )
Whoever it was might want these .
Let me see .
These are mine .
- These are my keys . - What are you talking about ?
- They 're mine . - Bullshit !
This ... This is my house key . This is my car key . This is my son .
See ?
Wait . You had them with you on the yacht ?
Yes .
It 's gotta be Heather .
- Come on ! - How else did they get here ?
Heather dropped her keys but didn 't bother to say , " I didn 't drown " ?
Well , why not ?
( Greg ) Come on .
Heather ?
Looks like you got your welcome party . Just not the welcome .
Oh , Greg , what time you got ?
About 11 : 30 .
( Sally ) Heather ?
Heather ?
( clinking )
Where is everyone ?
- Heather ? - Sally !
Please ... Please , I don 't , I don 't know where everyone is .
But the ship 's not deserted .
I mean , maybe someone wants us to think that it is , but it 's not .
So let 's just go to the bridge , find the skipper and then we 'll go home .
( footsteps )
- I saw someone . - ( Greg ) Fuck !
Wait !
( door bangs )
- ( distant bang ) - Hello ?
Well , did you see who it was ? Was it Heather ?
I didn 't see .
I 'm sorry .
Where are you going ?
- Why don 't you just help me out ? - What ?
( sighs ) Just wait for Vic .
- What ? - It 's OK , it 's fine .
Why can 't we go with him ?
Let 's just do as Greg says and wait here for Victor , OK ?
Fine .
- I think Victor is in danger . - I 'm not worried about Victor !
I 'm sorry I 'm acting weird , Greg ,
but I 'm having déja vu every time I turn a corner !
- No , no , no . - I know this place !
No , you don 't know this place . You 're just in shock !
- That 's not it . - What is it ? Is it Tommy ?
Is it guilt ? Is that what it is ? Do you feel guilty ?
( water runs )
Hello ?
( door creaks )
( water runs )
Hello ?
( distant bang )
( banging )
( seagulls cry )
Hello ?
- Around the third floor . - Greg .
- The bridge is two floors above us . - Greg , that was blood .
Are you just gonna ignore it ?
I know guys that work on ships like this . They get bored .
- They 're just ... letting off steam . - What ?
They rescue us from the sea and then they just hide for fun ?
Yeah .
- ( sighs ) - Well , what 's your theory ?
I don 't know , but I 'm not in shock .
I 'll be in the ballroom . I 'm getting off this ship .
Jess , fuck ! Don 't you see that this is all just in your mind ?
Jess ! Ships don 't magically appear out of nowhere . They have skippers .
I mean , in your world , right now , maybe they don 't .
My world is waiting outside school for his mother to pick him up .
Don 't talk to me about my world .
Hey , Jess ... Jess , I 'm sorry .
Shit .
Is that blood ?
Babe , come on , we 're supposed to meet them in the theatre .
Heather !
Oh , my God . Shit !
Sally ... Sal , come on .
Let 's just go to the theatre .
( sighs ) I can 't see any more blood . I don 't think she 's in here .
Honey , I don 't think she 's even on the ship .
OK , so whose blood was that ?
Hello ?
Downey ?
Sally ?
( door opens )
( door closes )
( footsteps )
Victor , what happened ?
( Victor grunts )
( Jess tries to scream )
( pants )
( gasps ) Oh , my God !
( gunshot )
( Sally sobs )
( Downey ) Stay with me , Greg .
- Stay with me . - ( Sally sobs )
( Downey ) Stay with me , man .
( sobs ) Downey , do something !
- No ! No ! - You fucking bitch ! You shot him !
- What ? - He said you shot him !
- I didn 't ! - God , you 're a liar ! A fucking liar !
- I wasn 't even with Greg ! - Jess , he is dead ! He 's dead !
Look !
God , you 're a bitch !
Oh , my ...
Get your hands off him !
I didn 't do it ! I was with Victor . ( pants )
- Someone attacked him . - Someone ?
You think I did it ?
Why did you tell us to come to the theatre ?
I didn 't ! I ... Sally , I didn 't .
- I didn 't . - My God , you 're a fucking schizo !
- ( gunshot ) - ( screams )
Sally , no !
- ( gunshot ) - ( Downey screams )
( both scream )
- ( Downey ) Jesus Christ ! - ( Sally ) Downey !
- ( gunshot ) - ( Downey screams )
- Sally ! - No !
( shrieks ) Oh , God , no , honey !
( Sally wails )
- Let him go . Let him go . - No !
Honey ! Honey !
( gunshot )
( distant bang )
( distant clanging )
( banging )
( metal clinks )
( running footsteps )
( grunts )
Don 't shoot ! Please !
Please don 't shoot . Please !
I have a son . I have a son .
( gun fires )
( bullet ricochets )
Shit !
( screams )
( groans )
( metal clangs )
( clang )
( weapon falls )
Who are you ? Tell me !
- ( woman ) They 'll return . - Who are you ?
And when they do , you have to kill them .
- What the fuck are you saying ? - It 's the only way to get home .
- What ? - You have to kill them .
Kill them ! Kill them ! Kill them !
( pants )
( seagull cries )
( Jazz music on a loop plays in the distance )
( needle scratches record )
( " Anchors Aweigh " by Glenn Miller and his Orchestra )
( distant shouting )
- ( Downey ) Help us ! - ( Greg ) Over here .
( Sally ) Help us !
( Downey ) Hey , help us !
- ( Greg ) Over here ! - ( Downey ) Hey , come on !
- ( Downey ) Hey , help us ! - ( Victor ) Over here !
( Downey ) Come on !
- ( Downey ) I see someone ! - ( Sally ) Help us ! Please !
- ( Downey ) Hello ! - ( Sally ) Help !
- ( Victor ) Down here ! - ( Greg ) Hello !
- Hey ! Hey ! - Down here !
- Help us ! Please ! - Hey !
There ! There , over there ! I can see somebody !
( Sally ) Please !
( Downey ) Come back !
( record plays on loop )
( Downey ) Hello ?
( Victor ) Looks like they scrapped the welcome .
( Greg ) Let 's go to the bridge .
We 'll get the captain to put a call out to the coastguard .
Hello ?
( Victor ) Hello ?
( Victor ) Where the fuck is everybody ?
( Downey ) Do you know where we 're going ?
( Downey ) Or are we just ... just walking for the sake of it ?
- Are you alright ? - I feel like I know this place .
I recognise this corridor .
Liners , they look ... pretty similar .
No , that 's not it .
Jess , come on .
( Victor ) If this is the same ship , then this thing 's old .
( Downey ) Yeah . 1932 , It is the same , see ?
Here 's where we boarded .
- ( Victor ) The Ay-oh-lus . - ( Downey ) Aeolus .
" Aeolus was the Greek God of the winds and father of Sisyphus ,
a man condemned to the task of pushing a rock up a mountain
only to have it roll down again . "
- Shitty punishment . What 'd he do ? - ( Sally ) He cheated death .
No , he made a promise to death that he didn 't keep .
I 've studied it but I can 't remember .
( keys clank )
( footsteps )
- ( Greg ) Hello ? - ( breathes heavily )
( water runs )
( engine drones )
( Sally ) Heather ?
( Victor ) Hello ?
- Heather ! - ( Greg ) Sally ! Please ...
Please , I don 't know where everyone is .
But the ship 's not deserted .
Maybe someone wants us to think that it is , but it 's not .
So let 's just go to the bridge , find the skipper and then we 'll go home .
( Jess ) I saw someone .
( seagulls cry )
( gasps )
( Victor ) Hello ?
Hello ?
Shit ! How did you get here so fast ?
Victor , you gotta listen to me . We don 't have much time .
- What 's going on ? Where 's Greg ? - He 's dead .
- What ? - No , no , no . I mean , he was dead .
- He 's not dead now . - What are you saying ?
Downstairs , right now , is a copy of myself .
Me , walking and talking with Greg !
Whoa , you 're ... What ?
Wait . No , no .
- There . - ( seagulls cry )
- Just birds . - That was Downey 's body .
I just left Downey back there .
- How did you get here so fast ? - That 's what I 'm trying to tell you .
No . Downey was there . It was ... It was Downey 's body !
There are bodies all over the ship .
Your body is on the floor of the restaurant with a hole in your head !
Listen , I 'm gonna do you a favour . I 'm not gonna tell anyone about this .
It 's the truth ! We 've gotta get off this ship right now .
- You 're saying there 's two of you ? - Yes .
- And I 'm dead ? - You were killed .
OK ! So , I 'm dead , Downey 's in the water and he 's dead , too .
Is Sally OK ? You see where I 'm going with this , right ?
If we 're dead and there 's two of you , how will we all get off this ship ?
We should never have boarded this ship . ( pants )
I knew something was wrong !
I should 've forced you to stay on the yacht , then you 'd all be alive !
I feel pretty alive right now .
- Soon you 'll be dead . - Easy !
- It happened to you before ! - I can 't even believe I 'm talking ...
It means you 're gonna die .
You 'll die , and then Downey and Sally and Greg !
( Victor gasps )
God !
( groans )
- ( grunts ) - I didn 't do this ! I didn 't do it !
( Greg ) We 're on the third level . The bridge should be exactly ...
( Jess ) Greg , that was blood . Are you just gonna ignore it ?
I know guys that work on ships like this . They get bored .
They 're just letting off steam .
( echoes ) Don 't you see that this is all just in your mind ?
Ships don 't magically appear out of nowhere . They have skippers .
In your world ... maybe they don 't .
( Jess ) My world is waiting outside school for his mother to pick him up .
Don 't talk to me about my world .
( metal clangs )
( pants )
( woman ) Who are you ?
Who are you ?
( woman 's voice echoes ) Who are you ?
Can you hear me ? Listen to me .
Please , you have to listen ! Who are you ?
If they board , kill them all .
If they board , kill them .
Who are you ?
Jess ! Jess , you 've got to kill them . Please , you have to listen .
Don 't let them board .
No , no , no . Please ... Please stop .
If they board , kill them . Jess ! Jess ! You 've got to kill them .
If they board , kill them .
No , please , please stop ! If they board , kill them .
Please ... Please stop . Jess ... Jess ... Jess ...
Fuck you !
( sobs )
( gasps ) Shit !
Tommy ...
( Sally ) Is that blood ?
Come on , we 're supposed to meet them in the theatre .
Victor .
I didn 't mean to hurt you .
You know I didn 't mean to hurt you , right ?
Now , I 'm gonna try and get us off this ship . OK ?
( Jess ) Sally ?
Sally ?
Victor , what happened ?
You 're not me .
( sobs )
You 're not me !
( gasps )
You see , I 'm not crazy .
Victor !
This didn 't happen before . Don 't you see ?
You tried to strangle me , remember ?
Be strong . I 'm gonna get the others .
( gunshot )
- ( sobs ) Downey , do something ! - Stay with me , man .
Oh , d-do something !
- I don 't know what to do . - Is he dead ?
Greg ! Are you OK ? ( sobs )
You fucking ... !
I won 't hurt you . But we dont have much time .
- Don 't point that thing at my wife ! - Move !
Go , go , go !
( gunshot )
I hit her . I think I hit her .
- What 's going on ? Who was that ? - It 's starting over again !
Let 's go .
- We can 't leave without Greg ! - We 'll come back for Greg .
Come on !
We can change the pattern . Don 't you see ?
If we change the pattern , we 're not trapped .
Then we can get off this thing .
- Jesus , she 's fucking nuts ! - You think ?
- You have to listen to me . - We don 't have to listen to you !
- Did I fire that shot ? - I don 't know !
Whoa , whoa ! Ladies ! Can we take a breath here for a second ?
I am prepared to listen . I 'm even prepared to believe you .
- But start making sense . - I am making perfect sense !
I 'm gonna get Victor , then we get off this ship .
Wait here .
And don 't trust anyone . If anyone comes , you shoot them .
- What are you talking about ? - You shoot them !
What ?
( crockery rattles )
Victor ?
( creaking )
( gunshot )
I said , who is it ?
It 's me . Jess .
Jesus Christ . What the fuck happened to you ?
Long story .
- Where 's Victor ? - He 's dead .
He fell over the side .
- How do we know you didn 't kill him ? - You don 't .
But if you wanna live , you 'll follow me .
- Downey ? - Ignore it .
( Jess ) Downey ?
- What 's going on ? - I said , ignore it .
Where are you ? Call out !
( Downey ) No , I am not just gonna ignore it . What is going on ?
( whispers ) Fuck , where are you ? Call out ! You 're in danger !
You 're in danger !
Who is that ?
Not who you think .
So , what are we doing in here ?
( screams )
( grunts )
( blood spurts / Jess withdraws blade )
Sally ! Wait !
- ( Jess grunts ) - ( Downey groans )
( pants )
I 'm sorry , but I love my son .
( Sally whimpers )
Sally ?
That wasn 't me !
( door clangs )
Sally ?
( sobs )
- ( static crackles ) - Hello ?
Hello ? Please , can you hear me ?
Help me . Please , help me .
She 's killing everyone ! They 're dead .
- They 're all dead ! Please help ! - ( Jess ) Sally ?
( Greg ) We hear you . What 's your position ? Over .
- Sally . - Distress caller ,
what are your coordinates ? Over .
( static )
Coastguard , did you hear a distress call ? Over .
Greg ?
- Greg , is that you ? - ( static )
Distress caller , make another transmission . What is your position ?
Greg , can you hear me ? Greg ?
( static )
Shit !
Sally ?
( hysterical sobbing )
( birds screech )
( whimpers )
- Oh , my God . What happened to you ? - ( mumbles ) Get away from me !
It wasn 't me , Sally . I didn 't do this to you .
It wasn 't me .
- Where 's Downey ? - You know where he is !
You killed him .
What ?
No , I didn 't . I didn 't kill him .
- What ? - I swear .
You 're crazy . Why are you doing this ?
Sally , I know it 's hard , but you gotta trust me .
You gotta trust me , OK ?
( clanging )
( grunts )
Listen , you 've gotta hold on . I think it 'll return again .
The yacht , the Triangle ... I think it 'll come back .
If it does , we 'll escape on it . Me and you together .
- We 'll reboard it and escape . - ( breathes heavily )
Please ...
Don 't hurt me .
Sally , I 'm not gonna hurt you .
If you hold on , you 'll get to see Downey again .
( seagulls cry )
( distant shouts )
( Victor ) Hey , over here ! Hey ! Hey !
( Greg ) Hey , help us ! Over here !
( Downey ) Hey , come on !
- ( Sally ) Help us ! - It returns when they 're dead .
- ( Greg ) There , I can see someone ! - ( Downey ) Hey , come back !
It returns when everyone 's dead .
( gasps )
( Sally ) Do you think Heather made it on board ?
- ( Downey ) Honey ... - ( Sally ) There 's a chance .
( Downey ) Yeah . Yeah , there 's a chance .
( steam hisses )
( grunts ) Stop this thing !
Stop this fucking thing !
Fuck off ! Fuck this !
- Fucking ... ! - ( steam hisses / engines chug )
Please ... ( sobs )
I wanna go home .
I wanna go home !
( Jess ) We don 't have much time .
- ( Victor ) Where 's Greg ? - He 's dead .
- ( Victor ) What ? - He was dead . He 's not dead now .
I was hiding in the funnels and I saw this version of myself .
She had blood on her face , and then I killed her on the front of the ship .
( Victor ) I 'm gonna do you a favour . I 'm not gonna tell anyone about this .
- ( Jess ) You 've gotta listen to me . - I 'm not listening to another word !
( Jess ) It means you 're gonna die !
You 'll die , and then Greg and then Downey !
( Victor groans )
( running footsteps )
( groans )
God ...
Don 't be scared , Victor . I can save you .
I know how to save you .
( water runs )
You should try and eat , babe .
Jess ?
Jesus , what happened to you ? Where 's Greg ?
Greg told me to tell you we should meet in the theatre .
There 's a theatre ?
Yes . It 's just that way .
- Where are you going ? - I 'll see you there .
OK , she 's really starting to freak me out now .
( Greg ) This is all just in your mind .
Ships just don 't magically appear out of nowhere . They have skippers .
In your world , maybe they don 't .
( Jess ) My world is waiting outside school for his mother to pick him up .
Don 't talk to me about my world .
( Greg ) Jess .
Jess , I 'm sorry .
- ( Jess pants ) - Whoa . H-Hey , just ...
OK .
- ( Greg ) Take it easy , man . - ( pants )
Just take it easy .
( breathes heavily )
What did we do ? We 're not part of this boat . We just got here , OK ?
We 've been walking around , there 's no one on it , you know .
I can go right now . I will go .
OK , just ... just take it easy .
Take it easy .
OK ?
( Greg gasps )
Jess ? Jess ?
Just what are you doing ? W-What is this ?
Why are you ... ? What are you wearing ?
I don 't want you to see my face .
- Why ? - ( pants ) Because this is not me .
I 'm somewhere out there on the upturned yacht and you 're with me .
And after I kill you , we 'll return .
Is that right ?
You know what , why don 't you just put down the gun first ?
( Greg ) OK ? Come on .
( Jess ) The boat comes back when you 're all dead .
I 've done everything like before , but when the boat comes back ,
I 'll be ready , I 'll be waiting . I 'll be on the landing bay .
I won 't let any of them board , even the other me .
I 'll make them all stay on the upturned yacht .
OK , Jess ,
we 'll do whatever you want . OK ?
Just ... Just put down the gun .
- Come on . - I 'm so sorry !
No , no , no , no !
( Sally ) Greg ! Oh , God ! Help him !
( Greg ) It was Jess .
( Sally ) You fucking bitch ! You shot him ! He said you shot him !
- ( Jess ) I wasn 't even with Greg ! - ( Sally ) Jess , he 's dead ! He 's dead !
( Sally ) My God , you 're a fucking schizo !
( Sally screams )
- ( Sally ) Downey ! - ( Downey groans )
( Sally sobs )
( Sally ) Oh , honey !
( Sally screams )
( groans )
Please !
Don 't kill me .
I have a son .
I have a son !
( gun fires )
No !
( Jess 1 ) Who are you ?
- ( Jess 1 ) Tell me ! - ( Jess 2 ) They 'll return .
( Jess 2 ) They 'll return . Kill them . It 's the only way to get home .
( Jess 1 ) What the fuck are you saying ?
( Jess 2 ) It 's the only way to save our son .
You have to kill them . Kill them ! Kill them !
( vehicle approaches )
( pants )
( lawnmower whirs )
( insects chirrup )
( breathes heavily )
( woman ) Hurry up , sweetheart , you 're gonna be late !
( door opens )
What 's the point in buying you things if leave them in the fucking garden ?
I 'm sick of telling you this , Tommy !
I ain 't buying you any more toys
if you can 't look after the ones you 've got !
( taps softly on window )
- ( paints pot falls ) - Now what ?
- I 'll just clean it up , shall 1 ? - ( Tommy gasps )
Yeah , I 'll just clean up the fucking mess !
What 's the matter with you ? Huh ? What 's the matter with you ?
Just one day off is all I ask ! Just one fucking day off !
I don 't know why you can 't paint a picture like a normal Kid .
You know , you get this from your father . He was an asshole , too !
( rings doorbell )
Shit !
Jack !
Did you see anyone ring my doorbell ?
( sighs )
( grunts )
( pants )
Tommy ...
Sweetheart , come here .
- ( Tommy screams ) - Come here , sweetheart , it 's OK .
- It 's OK . - ( whimpers )
Mommy 's fine , you see ?
( sobs ) Mommy 's fine .
You were just having a bad dream , that 's all , baby .
That 's all it was .
Bad dreams make you think you 've seen things that you haven 't .
( dog barks )
( seagull cries )
Things are gonna be different now , Tommy .
Mommy won 't lose her temper any more . Even when you do things wrong .
And she won 't hurt you .
I know she won 't hurt you .
You know how I know that , Tommy ?
Because that woman that did those things to you is not Mommy .
This is Mommy . Mommy 's nice .
- ( thud ) - Shit !
Shit !
( marching band plays )
- Bird , Mommy ! - Tommy , stay in the car .
Mommy will bury it , OK ?
( band plays " Anchors Aweigh " )
( breathes heavily )
- ( Tommy whimpers ) - We have to get out of here .
- Stop screaming , babe . - Blood !
- Please , Tommy . It 's just blood . - ( wails hysterically )
Stop screaming !
Tommy , look , see ? There . It 's gone . See ? There ? It 's gone .
( car creaks )
Are you alright ?
- Who are you ? - Just a driver .
No point trying to save the boy .
There 's nothing anyone can do that 's gonna bring him back .
Can I give you a ride ?
Yes .
Take me to the harbour .
( driver ) Hey .
I 'll leave the meter running .
You will come back , won 't you ?
Yes . I ... I promise .
( seagulls cry )
Jess .
Do you know me ?
I feel like I do . Greg talks about you enough .
- Where is Greg ? - Where do you think ?
Come on , you 're late .
- You 're the one with the kid , right ? - Yeah .
How come you didn 't bring him along ?
He 's at school .
- Are you sure about that ? - Yes .
- Are you OK ? - 1 don 't think so .
Hey , what 's the matter ? What happened ?
- Hey ! - I 'm sorry .
You 've got nothing to apologise for .
- What 's the matter ? - I 'm just tired , that 's ...
We don 't have to go today .
No , I do . | - I wanna go .
Are you sure ?
Yeah .
Yeah ? OK , come on .
- Sally , and her husband , Downey . - ( Sally ) Hi .
This is Heather . You remember Victor .
So let 's go sailing !
- ( Victor ) OK ! - ( Heather ) This is nice .
( seagull cries )